<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daniel Mangum</title>
    <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daniel Mangum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 13:21:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danielmangum.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Linux Command Line Using Docker</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/simple-linux-command-line-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 13:21:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/simple-linux-command-line-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker containers are widely used for developing and running anything from web applications to redis caches. However, they can also be useful for running what can effectively be a light VM (a container operates very differently from a VM, but we are just talking about the usecase). I like to use a container for accessing the the Linux command line. However, many users do not know how to run a container in the background and access the shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Kong API Gateway for Go Web Server</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/local-kong-go-web-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 15:52:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/local-kong-go-web-server/</guid>
      <description>This guide will teach you how to run the Kong API gateway locally as a proxy server for a Golang API using Docker.
The Go API The Golang standard library has a very simple http library that makes it very easy to spin up a web server. For now, we will build the simplest implementation of a web server. Start by creating a new directory in your go/src/.
mkdir go-api &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd $_ Then create a new file main.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I am Starting a Blog</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/why-i-am-starting-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 20:18:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/why-i-am-starting-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>I have always been envious of developers who share valuable information on their blog. I have thought for a long time that I wanted to be one of those developers that became famous in programming circles for the insight they shared. However, this also led me to be intimidated by the idea of writing my own posts. How could I ever measure up to these developers?
That mindset changed when I realized how much I had benefitted in work, school, and on personal projects from the blog posts of developers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>