<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daniel Mangum</title>
    <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daniel Mangum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 01:41:34 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danielmangum.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This Website is Hosted on Bluesky</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/this-website-is-hosted-on-bluesky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/this-website-is-hosted-on-bluesky/</guid>
      <description>Well, not this one. But this one is! How? Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at Bluesky and the AT Protocol that underpins it.
Note: I communicated with the Bluesky team prior to the publishing of this post. While the functionality described is not the intended use of the application, it is known behavior and does not constitue a vulnerability disclosure process. My main motivation for reaching out to them was because I like the folks and don&amp;rsquo;t want to make their lives harder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB On-The-Go on the ESP32-S3</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/usb-otg-esp32s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/usb-otg-esp32s3/</guid>
      <description>The ESP32-S3 is a popular microcontroller (MCU) for a variety of reasons, such as its support for external pseudostatic RAM (PSRAM). One of its lesser known features is its Universal Serial Bus (USB) On-The-Go (OTG) controller.
The previously released ESP32-S2, as well as the new ESP32-P4, also have USB OTG support, with the latter having two controllers.
USB OTG devices can act as a device or as a host. This is a popular feature for smartphones, which, when attached to a laptop or desktop should act as a device, but may want to act as a host for some peripherals, such as a keyboard, that may be attached to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is It Better to Fail Spectacularly?</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/better-to-fail-spectacularly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/better-to-fail-spectacularly/</guid>
      <description>Three weeks ago I wrote the following draft of a blog post entitled &amp;ldquo;Is It Better to Fail Spectacularly?&amp;rdquo;.
I am having a lot of doubts. I’ve been training for the Chicago Marathon in earnest since June, but in reality the preparations began a year ago when I was accepted based on my qualifying time from the 2023 Ventura Marathon. I don’t have doubt that I can run a marathon. I have run three in the last year and a half, and I routinely go on weekend long runs that approach or surpass 20 miles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Taxonomy of Hardware Security Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/taxonomy-hardware-security-mechanisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/taxonomy-hardware-security-mechanisms/</guid>
      <description>Isolating sensitive data and operations is a fundamental issue in computing. Ideally, we want to minimize the possibility of a software defect compromising the security of a device. However, in order for the software we write to be useful, it typically needs to interact with that sensitive data in some form or fashion. So how do we interact with sensitive data without being able to access it?
The answer is that we bring only the operations that must access the sensitive data closer to the data, then force all other software to invoke those operations via some sort of interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Founder Mode for Non-Founders</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/founder-mode-non-founders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/founder-mode-non-founders/</guid>
      <description>Paul Graham’s Founder Mode essay, based on a recent talk from AirBnB founder Brian Chesky, has been getting quite a lot of attention over the past few days. It has prompted many a quote tweet, and founders, such as Bryan Cantrill of Oxide Computer, have started contributing their own thoughts to what founder mode means to them.
Having held positions of influence at a few companies, but never having been a founder myself, my initial read raised a few thoughts about my own experience of trying to “scale myself” in a growing organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Allocation in External RAM on ESP32</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/static-alloc-external-ram-esp32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/static-alloc-external-ram-esp32/</guid>
      <description>I frequently work with ESP32 microcontrollers (MCU), both at my day job and in my free time. These devices are very flexible, but like any microcontroller they are quite resource constrained in comparison to anything equivalent to or larger than a single-board computer.
There are a few different variants of the ESP32 these days, but one of the newer and most popular is the ESP32-S3. Compared to the ESP32-S2, it offers a dual-core 32-bit Xtensa processor, support for Bluetooth 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframes are Cheap, Engineering Should Be Too</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/wireframes-cheap-engineering-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/wireframes-cheap-engineering-too/</guid>
      <description>I have spent the majority of my career in engineering roles at startups. Both at companies I have worked at, and in the general startup ecosystem, I have frequently heard some variation of the refrain “engineers are expensive, but wireframes are cheap”. While I align with the underlying sentiment that doing the least amount of work to get customer signal is optimal, the phrase has always bothered me.
As an engineering leader, I do not want the rest of the organization to view the work that my colleagues and I do as some luxury that should only be leveraged after we have reached complete confidence that a product or feature needs to be built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Skill in Startup Engineering Leadership</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/most-important-skill-startup-engineering-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/most-important-skill-startup-engineering-leadership/</guid>
      <description>I have been very fortunate to have both worked alongside some incredible engineering leaders, as well as lead engineering teams myself. These experiences have primarily been in the context of startups that are growing rapidly in terms of both customers and employees. The longer I have worked in these environments, the more convinced I have become that there is a singular skill that ultimately decides the success of a leader, and thus their team: pacing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Accessing the Pinecil UART with picoprobe</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-accessing-pinecil-uart-picoprobe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-accessing-pinecil-uart-picoprobe/</guid>
      <description>This post is the second in a RISC-V Bytes subseries on the PINE64 Pinecil soldering iron and development board. Previous and subsequent posts can be found under the RISC-V Bytes category.
In the most recent Pinecil post, we walked through how to solder the header pins on the Pinecil breakout board. With the headers attached, we can now communicate with the Pinecil&amp;rsquo;s microcontroller via a number of protocols. Today we are going to focus on accessing the Universal Asynchronous Receiver / Transmitter (UART) hardware in order to receive serial data from the microcontroller, such as log messages, on a development machine (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Soldering the Pinecil Breakout Board</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-soldering-pinecil-breakout-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-soldering-pinecil-breakout-board/</guid>
      <description>This post is the first in a RISC-V Bytes subseries on the PINE64 Pinecil soldering iron and development board. Subsequent posts can be found under the RISC-V Bytes category.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the Pinecil as my primary soldering iron for a few months now. The neat thing about the Pinecil is that it is not only a highly portable USB-C powered iron, but it is also an interesting RISC-V development board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Running 3,000 Miles in 2023</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/3000-miles-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/3000-miles-2023/</guid>
      <description>I spent the final week of 2022 feeling extremely sick, mostly confined to a bed. I was particularly disappointed in getting sick at that point in the year given that I was wrapping up the best running year of my life. I was very consistent with training, ran a few races, and was closing in on 1,400 miles. I am a big proponent of setting ambitious goals, and will go to pretty extreme lengths to reach them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Every Byte in a WASM Module</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/every-byte-wasm-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/every-byte-wasm-module/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, we explored how to build WASM modules, both with and without WASI support, using Clang. In a comment on Reddit, it was mentioned that much of the setup I walked through in that post could be avoided by just leveraging Zig&amp;rsquo;s WASI supprt. This is a great point, and I would recommend doing the same. The following command is inarguably simpler than what I described.
$ zig cc --target=wasm32-wasi However, there are two reasons why knowing how to use Clang for compilation is useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero to WASI with Clang 17</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/wasm-wasi-clang-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/wasm-wasi-clang-17/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working on a few projects that involve leveraging WebAssembly (WASM) modules, particularly with WebAssembly System Interface (WASI) support. While WASI is still in its early stages, support has already been added to the Rust compiler and Clang, as well as runtimes such as wasmtime and WAMR. However, getting an environment setup to compile arbitrary C programs to WASM can still be challenging.
I recently updated to Clang 17, which was first released as 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercon 2023 Day 3: badgecase.io</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/supercon-2023-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/supercon-2023-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Screenshot of Badgecase gallery page.
The final day of Supercon 2023 had more great talks, including an incredible recollection of Restoring the Apollo Guidance Computer. However, the real highlight was seeing all of the various badge hacks starting to take their final form, ultimately culminating with the Badge Hacking Ceremony at the end of the day.
Mike and I had made enough progress on Saturday after pivoting away from our PIO / DMA exploits that the remaining work on Sunday morning primarily revolved around final hardware setup and managing DNS records (riveting stuff I know!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercon 2023 Day 2: Talks Begin, Hacking Continues</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/supercon-2023-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/supercon-2023-day-2/</guid>
      <description>The energy from Friday at Supercon 2023 carried over into Saturday, and adding a stream of ongoing talks to the badge hacking and hallway track made it feel like even more was going on. The setup today was the traditional Supercon &amp;ldquo;hacker alley&amp;rdquo;, with the two talk venues connected by a long, narrow corridor packed with people, parts, and soldering irons. Space was at a premium, but interesting conversation was readily available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercon 2023 Day 1: Hello Badge</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/supercon-2023-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/supercon-2023-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Just a few minutes after arriving at Hackaday Supercon 2023, I decided that I needed to document my experience. Working with two longtime Supercon veterans (they literally started the thing!), I had been adequately prepared for experiencing the event for the first time, but there is nothing quite like actually being there in-person. Even at 9 AM on Friday, the energy and activity was already bubbling. Despite not knowing many folks, or only knowing of them by their online presence, I felt as though I was attending a gathering of old friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Verible for Verilog with Neovim</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/setup-verible-verilog-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/setup-verible-verilog-neovim/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Vivado for moss RTL development, which, despite its notoriously large install size, offers a fairly decent developer experience.
Or maybe I have just been using it for too long. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I would have said this a few months ago.
However, I still prefer to write Verilog in Neovim, as it allows me to use vim motions, as well as switch between RTL and software code without changing my workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Particularly Gnarly Case of Go’s Non-Nil Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/go-gnarly-non-nil-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/go-gnarly-non-nil-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>Most seasoned Go programmers are familiar with the memory representation of an interface. In fact, A Tour of Go, the canonical starting point for new Go programmers, makes sure to describe how interface values contain a value and a type (for a more specific description, see Russ Cox’s blog post on how interfaces are implemented), and even goes so far as to distinguish between interface values with nil underlying values and nil interface values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How LUTs Are Used as Storage Elements on an FPGA</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/how-luts-used-storage-fpga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/how-luts-used-storage-fpga/</guid>
      <description>If you are interested in what went into writing this blog post, you can view a replay of the livestream here.
In a recent post we explored when Vivado inferred Block RAM (BRAM) for memories in FPGA designs, and when it used distributed RAM instead. While it is somewhat obvious why BRAM can be used for memory in an FPGA (i.e. it is literally a discrete memory element), distributed RAM is a bit more complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Livestreaming Long-Term Projects</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/value-livestreaming-long-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/value-livestreaming-long-term/</guid>
      <description>This is less of a blog post, and more of a collection of Friday thoughts that occurred to me on my morning run. Last night I was livestreaming some work on a new moss blog post in which I describe the use of Look-Up Tables (LUTs) as storage elements on an FPGA (this will be published in a few days). However, I ended up spending the majority of the time scouring the internet for documentation on the relationship between 5-input LUTs (LUT5) and 6-input LUTs (LUT6) on Xilinx 7 Series FPGAs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Does Vivado Infer BRAM?</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/when-vivado-infer-bram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/when-vivado-infer-bram/</guid>
      <description>If you are interested in what went into writing this blog post, you can view a replay of the livestream here.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the logic design for moss, I have been regularly investigating how Vivado translates the Verilog RTL (Register Transfer Level) source into Basic Elements of Logic (BELs), a process known as synthesis. BELs represent the physical components on an FPGA that can be used to implement a design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microprocessors Are Tiny, But They Can’t Fit in Your Head</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/microprocessors-tiny-cant-fit-in-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/microprocessors-tiny-cant-fit-in-head/</guid>
      <description>I have not been able to make as much progress on moss over the last 14 days or so as I would like, in large part because of limited time due to getting some exciting work across the finish line at $dayjob. However, whenever I find myself limited in the amount of “hands on keyboard” time I have to spend on a project, I try to invest more of my idle brain time (IBT, if you will) thinking about the next stages of development, as well as higher level long-term goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Retrospective on SPARC Register Windows</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/retrospective-sparc-register-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/retrospective-sparc-register-windows/</guid>
      <description>As I work on moss and research modern processor design patterns and techniques, I am also looking for patterns and techniques from the past that, for one reason or another, have not persisted into our modern machines. While on a run this week, I was listening to an old Oxide and Friends episode where Bryan, Adam, and crew were reminiscing on the SPARC instruction set architecture (ISA). SPARC is a reduced instruction set computer (RISC) architecture originally developed by Sun Microsystems, with the first machine, the SPARCstation1 (a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Dissect a Critical HackerNews Comment</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/how-to-dissect-critical-hackernews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/how-to-dissect-critical-hackernews/</guid>
      <description>Note: while I was writing this post, Julia Evans published a wonderful entry on her blog entitled Some tactics for writing in public. I highly recommend reading as it includes some wonderful guidance about how to preempt some of the discussion I reference in this post, as well as a short but highly relevant section on analyzing negative comments. You can think of this post as putting some of that theory into practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Single-Cycle 64-Bit RISC-V Register File</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/single-cycle-rv64-register-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/single-cycle-rv64-register-file/</guid>
      <description>It’s a simple question really: how can you read and write to the same register in a single-cycle processor? If you have spent most of your life working with software, it is tempting to think of all events as happening sequentially. However, that sequential model that we have become so familiar with as software engineers is really an abstraction that hardware offers to us to help our simple brains reason about logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-Cycle and Multicycle Do Not Describe Processor Performance</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/single-cycle-multicycle-processor-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/single-cycle-multicycle-processor-performance/</guid>
      <description>If you read most literature about processor design, you’ll inevitably be presented with three broad categories of CPU architectures:
Single-Cycle Multicycle Pipelined We’ll just be focusing on the first two for today.
In fact, my favorite introductory book on computer architecture, Computer Organization and Design (Patterson &amp;amp; Hennessy) progresses through Chapter 4: The Processor by explaining these three models in sequence. The first big idea can be synthesized into the following logic:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Create a New Instruction Set Architecture?</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/why-create-new-isa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/why-create-new-isa/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: even if you&amp;rsquo;re not being pragmatic, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need to.
One of the things I have been thinking about while starting to work on moss again is whether I should implement one of the many RISC-V flavors, or whether I should design an entirely new instruction set architecture (ISA). Designing a new one might seem like the ultimate bike-shedding effort, and if my immediate goal was getting something useful into production, I almost certainly would not embark on the journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Three Year Bet on Chip Design</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/a-three-year-bet-on-chip-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/a-three-year-bet-on-chip-design/</guid>
      <description>I turn 27 years old today, which feels both very old and very young. 30 is often seen as a milestone, perhaps because you have spent nearly a decade operating as an “adult”, but likely are still considered in the earlier part of your career. I am a firm believer that doing most things of significance takes at least 3 years, which makes 27 a good time to decide to commit to “doing something before you are 30”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Semihosting with Zephyr on an ESP32</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-semihosting-zephyr-esp32/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-semihosting-zephyr-esp32/</guid>
      <description>Note: all analysis and code samples used in this post correspond to the v3.3.0 release of Zephyr.
Having a good debugging workflow is critical to developing software quickly with high confidence. Fortunately, writing software for computers is often done, well, on a computer, meaning that while writing programs we can run other programs that help us understand the behavior of what we are writing. Typically the machine we are writing software for, though it may run in a data center and have a different form factor, doesn&amp;rsquo;t look so different from the machine we are writing it on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Zephyr Before Main</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-zephyr-before-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-zephyr-before-main/</guid>
      <description>In the last two posts in the RISC-V Bytes series we have looked at a bootloader for the ESP32-C3, then built a Zephyr application that was loaded by it. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look at that &amp;ldquo;Hello, World&amp;rdquo; application, diving into what happens prior to printing our message to the UART console.
Note: all analysis and code samples used in this post correspond to the v3.3.0 release of Zephyr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Zephyr on the ESP32</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-zephyr-on-esp32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-zephyr-on-esp32/</guid>
      <description>In the most recent post in the RISC-V Bytes series, we had our first experience with real hardware, exploring the bootloader on an ESP32-C3-DevKitC-02 module. We were using esp-idf, which, behind the scenes uses an implementation of FreeRTOS. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll swap out the Espressif FreeRTOS implementation for Zephyr, exploring some similarities and differences between the build process and produced artifacts. We&amp;rsquo;ll also see how we can slim down a Zephyr installation, only fetching the code and tools that we need to target the ESP32-C3 chipset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Exploring a Custom ESP32 Bootloader</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-exploring-custom-esp32-bootloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-exploring-custom-esp32-bootloader/</guid>
      <description>I recently acquired an ESP32-C3-DevKitC-02 module, and, as I tend to do, jumped right into reading about how the system boots and how the (pretty good!) tooling Espressif offers works. We have typically used QEMU in the RISC-V Bytes series, but getting our hands on physical hardware starts to make things feel a bit more real. In this first post on the ESP32, we&amp;rsquo;ll do some basic setup and look at a simple custom bootloader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you want to take a leap of faith?</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/leap-of-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/leap-of-faith/</guid>
      <description>Upbound reached General Availability on Tuesday and today is my last day at the company. It feels surreal to write that, despite knowing this day was coming for quite some time. With my time coming to a close, I wanted to take a moment to reflect on one of the most wonderful and impactful experiences of my life.1
Joining Upbound Link to heading Inception is one of my favorite movies.2 I’ve always loved the scene, and the subsequent callback to it, where Cobb is deciding whether to accept Saito’s proposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where does the kubelet mount volumes?</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/where-does-the-kubelet-mount-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/where-does-the-kubelet-mount-volumes/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t have time to read this post? I get it. The answer to your question is /var/lib/kubelet/&amp;lt;pod-id&amp;gt;/volumes/.
Every so often I will be pairing with someone or showing off a demo and realize that some common operation I perform is not well-documented. We all have examples of domain knowledge we learned somewhere along the way and stashed in our toolbox. Whenever I encounter these situations I try to remember to post about them so that the next person can find the information at least a little bit faster than I did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s ASA: Watching and Caching</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/k8s-asa-watching-and-caching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/k8s-asa-watching-and-caching/</guid>
      <description>In our most recent post in the Kubernetes API Server Adventures series we took a look at the storage interface and explored the only in-tree implementation: etcd3. However, a careful read of the footnotes in that post revealed I wasn&amp;rsquo;t being completely honest about etcd3 being the only implementation.
This could be disputed as Cacher is technically an implementation as well. However, it requires an underlying implementation in order to perform its operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s ASA: The Storage Interface</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/k8s-asa-the-storage-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/k8s-asa-the-storage-interface/</guid>
      <description>Like most API servers, a, if not the, primary function of the Kubernetes API Server is to ingest data, store it, then return it when requested. Today we are going to be focusing on how the API Server stores data.
Table of Contents:
The apiserver Module (👈 &amp;ldquo;I want all the details.&amp;rdquo;) The storage Package Our Good Friend etcd The API Server and etcd Calling storage.Interface Directly (👈 &amp;ldquo;Can we skip the background info?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Kubernetes API Server Adventures</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/k8s-asa-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/k8s-asa-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes is comprised of a variety of components, yet most end-user interaction with the system flows through the API Server. It is the entrypoint to many of the features that the project has built up over its lifetime, and can be extended to support arbitrary additional functionality. Because of this, the API Server has proved to be a bottleneck in some cases that it was not originally designed to accommodate, or at least accommodate well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Timer Interrupts</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-timer-interrupts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-timer-interrupts/</guid>
      <description>Operating systems do great work, but sometimes they need a little bit of help to know when to switch from one task to another. Thankfully, hardware is there to help! Today we are going to take a look at how operating systems schedule reminders for themselves using timer interrupts.
Sections Link to heading Don&amp;rsquo;t care about the why and just want to see the code? Jump ahead to The Full Picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m on Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/im-on-mastodon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/im-on-mastodon/</guid>
      <description>Twitter has been a huge part of my online community, but it has become untenable as a platform. I have found a nice community of folks over on the types.pl server. I would love to reconnect with all of the wonderful people I have interacted with on Twitter and elsewhere. You can find me at @hasheddan@types.pl!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Go 1.19&#39;s Register-Based Calling Convention</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-go-1-19-register-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-go-1-19-register-calling/</guid>
      <description>In our last post in the RISC-V Bytes series, I briefly alluded to the proposal to switch the Go Application Binary Interface (ABI) from a stack-based calling convention to a register-based calling convention. I also mentioned that it appeared at that time that the RISC-V port would support the new calling convention as early as Go 1.19.
Last week, Go 1.19 was officially released, and sure enough, tucked in the release notes was a section mentioning that the riscv64 port now supports passing arguments and results using registers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Stack Use After Return in C, Go, and Rust</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-stack-use-after-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-stack-use-after-return/</guid>
      <description>If you write any code that deals with manual memory management, you are likely familiar with the concept of a &amp;ldquo;use after free&amp;rdquo; bug. These bugs can be the source of, at best, program crashes, and at worst serious vulnerabilities. A lesser discussed counterpart to use after free, is &amp;ldquo;use after return&amp;rdquo;. In some cases, the latter can be even more troublesome, due to the operations that are performed when one procedure calls another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sandbox Programmers</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/sandbox-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/sandbox-programmers/</guid>
      <description>As a relatively young person in the technology industry who is interested in low-level software and designing hardware, but spends most of my day job working on backend and distributed systems, I frequently find myself lamenting the fact that many folks in my generation mostly grew up in a world where compute is thought of more in terms of an infinite abstract resource, rather than a capability of a physical machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graceful Shutdown of Responsibilities in a Growing Organization</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/graceful-shutdown-responsibilities-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/graceful-shutdown-responsibilities-organization/</guid>
      <description>I usually write about deep technical topics, frequently going into extreme detail about how systems work. I love a good technical challenge, but recently the most challenging thing I have been working on at my day job has not been technical.
Achieving Outsized Impact Link to heading I joined Upbound essentially straight out of college after working on the open source Crossplane project on nights and weekends. The team was quite small and quite senior at that point, making me a bit of an anomaly in the organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Kubernetes Type System</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/the-missing-kubernetes-type-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/the-missing-kubernetes-type-system/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I hear folks in the Crossplane community ask if they can just use Helm instead of opting into our package manager. The technical answer to this question is &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo;, but it typically represents a misinterpretation of what Crossplane is providing in a Kubernetes cluster. That being said, I completely understand why someone would ask this question, and quite frankly, I think the confusion is our fault. In Crossplane and across the Kubernetes community we lean in heavily to the idea that everything is &amp;ldquo;just an object&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Rust Cross-Compilation</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-rust-cross-compilation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-rust-cross-compilation/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series on the blog where we explore RISC-V by breaking down real programs and explaining how they work. You can view all posts in this series on the RISC-V Bytes page.
Today we are going to take a brief detour from our previous posts in this series and look at Rust Cross-Compilation for RISC-V. This will be a shorter post focused on providing useful information about how rustc works, as well as offering exact steps and configuration to target RISC-V when compiling your Rust programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Privilege Levels</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-privilege-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-privilege-levels/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series on the blog where we explore RISC-V by breaking down real programs and explaining how they work. You can view all posts in this series on the RISC-V Bytes page.
It has been a bit since our last post, but today we are going to begin our journey into some of the more interesting areas of RISC-V systems. In the first post in the series, we installed our RISC-V toolchain, which included QEMU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Kubernetes Validates Custom Resources</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/how-kubernetes-validates-custom-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/how-kubernetes-validates-custom-resources/</guid>
      <description>This post references the Kubernetes codebase at commit d92a443ca7 and kube-openapi at commit ee342a809c, but should remain mostly applicable for an extended period of time barring any massive refactor to Kubernetes internals. This is also intended to be a very active read and a reference to come back to over time. There are a lot of links to source code that is not embedded because the post would have become even more unwieldy than it already is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure in Your Software Packages</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/infrastructure-in-your-software-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/infrastructure-in-your-software-packages/</guid>
      <description>This post explores what a future of shipping infrastructure alongside software may look like by detailing where we are today, and evaluating how the delivery of software has evolved over time. If you just want the big ideas, skip to the final section: A New Kind of Software Marketplace.
Almost all software depends on infrastructure. Installation documentation typically has a section detailing how to run with your favorite cloud provider managed services, and, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, may even include a script to provision that infrastructure for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Introduction to Instruction Formats</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-intro-instruction-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:10:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-intro-instruction-formats/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series on the blog where we explore RISC-V by breaking down real programs and explaining how they work. You can view all posts in this series on the RISC-V Bytes page.
So far in this series, we have been looking at the assembly generated when compiling relatively simple programs. At this point, we have seen instructions that perform a wide variety of operations. Let&amp;rsquo;s take another look at our minimal example from the Passing on the Stack post:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Research Triangle RISC-V Community Group</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/research-triangle-risc-v-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/research-triangle-risc-v-group/</guid>
      <description>I am excited to announce the launch of the Research Triangle RISC-V Community Group!
As evidenced by my recent posts and conference talks, I have been spending more and more time learning and working in and around the RISC-V community. While there are numerous commercial benefits of an open source instruction set architecture (ISA), I am particularly excited about the opportunities it provides for folks like myself who do not have formal training in processor design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Passing on the Stack</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-passing-on-the-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-passing-on-the-stack/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series on the blog where we explore RISC-V by breaking down real programs and explaining how they work. You can view all posts in this series on the RISC-V Bytes page.
I once took a class on compilers where my professor told us that a CPU is like a human brain: it can store important data and access it quickly, but there is a limit to the amount of data that can be stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stepping Away from Upstream Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/stepping-away-upstream-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/stepping-away-upstream-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>This post is adapted from my message sent to the Kubernetes SIG Release mailing list.
I got involved in the Kubernetes community right after finishing school, primarily by working on the tooling used to test and release each of the components of the project. From the beginning, I was shown a tremendous amount of respect and care, and that has remained constant since. That being said, over the past two years I have seen my interests evolve rapidly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Caller and Callee Saved Registers</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-caller-callee-registers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-caller-callee-registers/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a new series I am starting on the blog where we’ll explore RISC-V by breaking down real programs and explaining how they work. You can view all posts in this series on the RISC-V Bytes page.
When looking at the generated assembly for a function, you may have noticed that the first few instructions involve moving values from registers to the stack, then loading those values back into the same registers before returning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Cross-Platform Debugging with QEMU and GDB</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-qemu-gdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-qemu-gdb/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a new series I am starting on the blog where we&amp;rsquo;ll explore RISC-V by breaking down real programs and explaining how they work. You can view all posts in this series on the RISC-V Bytes page.
To start of the series, we are just going to get setup to do some exploration. I am going to assume you will not primarily be using a RISC-V machine1, so we need to configure our local development environment for cross-platform compiling, emulation, and debugging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a ConfigMap as an OCI Image Cache</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/config-map-oci-image-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/config-map-oci-image-cache/</guid>
      <description>For folks familiar with Crossplane, you likely know that we adopt the design practice of using interfaces over implementations as frequently as possible. Even if we begin with an implementation, such as the current composition engine, we make sure to consider a future with potentially many implementations for the same functionality.
One of the places where we have taken advantage of Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; similar approach to interfaces is in how we cache Crossplane package images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chdir to cwd: permission denied</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/runc-chdir-to-cwd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/runc-chdir-to-cwd/</guid>
      <description>This post describes a breaking change in runc v1.0.0-rc93, that has subsequently had a workaround implemented that will presumably be included in v1.0.0-rc94. Thanks to @haircommander for talking through the issue with me and implementing the subsequent workaround, and to @mattomata for his consultation on the distroless/static:nonroot behavior. If you are not interested in the background of the issue, you can skip reading this post and take a look at my detailed testing scenarios on the Crossplane repo, or my breakdown of the conflict with the nonroot image on the distroless repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Crossplane the Infrastructure LLVM?</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/crossplane-infrastructure-llvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/crossplane-infrastructure-llvm/</guid>
      <description>If I was to explain LLVM in a painfully simple manner, I might say something like: &amp;ldquo;LLVM is a framework that allows you to define a syntax for interacting with computers, and instantly have it work for all computers&amp;rdquo;. This description does a colossal disservice to the scope of the project, but it serves to illustrate the basic idea: there are many languages (frontends) and many CPU architectures (backends) and we don&amp;rsquo;t want to re-implement every translation permutation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping controller-runtime Prometheus Metrics Locally</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/controller-runtime-scrape-prometheus-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/controller-runtime-scrape-prometheus-local/</guid>
      <description>controller-runtime exposes a metrics server by default on port 8080 for any controller Manager. Metrics are registered for the client, workqueue, and on a per-controller basis.
Controllers initialize metrics when started, and write to the registry at various points throughout operation, such as when processing items off the workqueue and after completed reconciliation loops. If you are using a framework like Kubebuilder, it will generate manifests for the necessary objects, such as a ServiceMonitor, to scrape these metrics using kube-prometheus in your Kubernetes cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rate Limiting in controller-runtime and client-go</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/controller-runtime-client-go-rate-limiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/controller-runtime-client-go-rate-limiting/</guid>
      <description>If you have written a Kubernetes controller, you are likely familiar with controller-runtime, or at least client-go. controller-runtime is a framework for building controllers that allows consumers to setup multiple controllers that are all handled under a controller manager. Behind the the scenes, controller-runtime is using client-go to communicate with the Kubernetes API server to watch for changes on resources and pass them along to the relevant controllers. It handles a number of aspects of plumbing up these controllers, including caching, queuing, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Talk: Building an Enterprise Infrastructure Control Plane on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/kubecon-na-20-infra-control-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 05:51:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/kubecon-na-20-infra-control-plane/</guid>
      <description>I had the privilege of joining Steven Borrelli from Mastercard for a tutorial at Kubecon North America 2020 on building an enterprise infrastructure control plane on Kubernetes using Crossplane. Relevant links and the talk recording can be found below.
Slide Deck Source Code Text Transcript Please feel free to send me a message @hasheddan on Twitter with any questions or comments!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Vivado 2020.x on Ubuntu 20.04</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/vivado-2020-x-ubuntu-20-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 05:51:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/vivado-2020-x-ubuntu-20-04/</guid>
      <description>Vivado is Xilinx&amp;rsquo;s IDE for HDL synthesis and analysis. It is a powerful tool, but can be a bit of a pain to setup and use. I recently went through the installation process on my main development machine, where I cam currently running Ubuntu 20.04, after I purchased a Digilent Arty A7-35T development board, which is designed around the Xilinx Artix-7 FPGA. While it didn&amp;rsquo;t take too long to get up and running (ignoring the time waiting for the actual installation to complete), I found the existing installation documentation quite verbose, which made following along more difficult than it should have been.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweet Thread: Crossplane Packages and K8s Features You Thought You Didn&#39;t Have</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/crossplane-packages-k8s-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:51:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/crossplane-packages-k8s-features/</guid>
      <description>The following is an unroll of a tweet thread about Crossplane packages that I posted after reading Dave Anderson&amp;rsquo;s post &amp;ldquo;A better Kubernetes, from the ground up&amp;rdquo;. I found many of the points in the post compelling, but feel that the existing extensibility model of Kubernetes allows for implementing at least some of the desired features without tearing down the entire system, as evidenced by the implementation of Crossplane packages. It is my hope that some of the design decisions we have made with Crossplane can be generally abstracted and improved upon to continue to enhance the Kubernetes ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Non-Local Jumps (setjmp/longjmp) in RISC-V Assembly</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/non-local-jumps-riscv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 18:51:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/non-local-jumps-riscv/</guid>
      <description>This post explores RISC-V assembly by examining the implementation of the setjmp and longjmp functions from the C standard library. I frequently find that I grasp concepts more quickly when I have actual code that I can disassemble because it allows me to connect information with intent. I believe RISC-V and similar efforts will fundamentally shift how computers are made and programmed. I hope that sharing my knowledge will inspire the same joy in others that I feel when imagining a future of open hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Guest: Using Kubernetes And Crossplane To Provision Cloud Infrastructure (Full Stack Journey)</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/podcast-fullstackjourney-crossplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 18:51:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/podcast-fullstackjourney-crossplane/</guid>
      <description>I joined Scott Lowe on the Full Stack Journey podcast for a chat about how Crossplane enables you to provision infrastructure from your Kubernetes cluster and allows you to compose abstractions that define your own PaaS. You can listen here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uppercase .S vs Lowercase .s File Extensions in GAS Syntax Assembly</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/upper-v-lower-extensions-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 18:51:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/upper-v-lower-extensions-assembly/</guid>
      <description>If you have ever written assembly for the GNU Assembler (GAS), you may have noticed that files sometimes have an .S extension and sometimes .s. This is not a meaningless distinction, and you could have a frustrating time if you accidentally use the wrong one.
The uppercase .S indicates that the file contents should be run through the preprocessor, while the lowercase .s indicates that the file contents should be assembled directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Guest: What is Rapid Prototyping? (The DroidDevCast)</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/podcast-droiddevcast-rapid-prototyping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 18:51:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/podcast-droiddevcast-rapid-prototyping/</guid>
      <description>I joined Rin Oliver on the esper.io DroidDevCast for a chat about rapid prototyping. You can listen here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Guest: Daniel Mangum on Crossplane, building a PaaS, and Multi-Cluster Kubernetes (LOTE)</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/podcast-lote-crossplane-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 18:51:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/podcast-lote-crossplane-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>I joined Daniel Bryant on the Ambassador Livin’ on the Edge podcast for a chat about Crossplane, building your own PaaS, and the future of multi-cluster Kubernetes. You can listen here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Post: Adding Managed Services to Serverless with Crossplane and OpenFaaS (OpenFaaS Blog)</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/crossplane-openfaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 14:39:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/crossplane-openfaas/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to write up a recap and guide for the livestream I did with Alex Ellis on using Crossplane with OpenFaas. It is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Post: Connecting AWS managed services to your Argo CD pipeline with open source Crossplane (AWS Open Source Blog)</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/crossplane-aws-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 14:39:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/crossplane-aws-open-source/</guid>
      <description>I had the privilege of writing a guest post on the AWS Open Source Blog entitled &amp;ldquo;Connecting AWS managed services to your Argo CD pipeline with open source Crossplane&amp;rdquo;. You can read it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Guest: Gerhard goes to KubeCon (part 2) (The Changelog)</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/podcast-changelog-kubecon-crossplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 18:51:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/podcast-changelog-kubecon-crossplane/</guid>
      <description>Jared Watts, Marques Johansson, and I sat down for a chat about Crossplane and the cloud native community with Gerhard Lazu on the Changelog Podcast at Kubecon North America 2019. You can listen here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Mind Your Metaphors</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/please-mind-your-metaphors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:07:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/please-mind-your-metaphors/</guid>
      <description>Note: While writing this post, I looked back at a post I wrote entitled Understanding ETL to ELT by Going to Costco. That post does exactly what I say we should not do in this post. It takes a process and explains it using a metaphor that cannot hope to fully encompass what I try to say. I do think that metaphors can be somewhat useful when attempting to give a high-level overview of a subject, but I think I did it rather poorly in that post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HashiCode Ep. 1: Terraform Remote State Backend Locking</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/tf-remote-state-backend-locking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:31:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/tf-remote-state-backend-locking/</guid>
      <description>This is the first installment of HashiCode, a blog post series where I go through the source code of HashiCorp tools to learn more about what happens behind the scenes when you interact with tools as a user.
Disclaimer: this episode is referencing code from the Terraform codebase as of commit 43a7548. Becuase Terraform is a constanly evolving open source tool, the code is subject to change. However, the ideas expressed will largely remain the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing HashiCode</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/introducing-hashicode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:21:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/introducing-hashicode/</guid>
      <description>Today I am excited to announce a new series of blog posts called HashiCode. I have been involved with the HashiCorp community for some time now, and I have loved the opportunity to contribute to some of my favorite tools because of the open source model of the company. Recently, I have been organizing the new HashiCorp User Group in St. Louis, a market that is starting to show a lot of interest in the various products the company offers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presence vs. Planning</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/presence-vs-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 16:36:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/presence-vs-planning/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I find it hard to focus on the work I am doing. It can be easy to constantly be evaluating how everything you are doing affects the present, affects your future, and affects those around you. These are good questions to be asking, but at the right time. If we are always planning, how are we ever going to get anything done? On the other hand, if we are never planning, how do we have context when choosing what to do next?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding ETL to ELT by Going to Costco</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/etl-to-elt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 14:39:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/etl-to-elt/</guid>
      <description>If you have dealt with any data platform in the last few years, you have likely heard about the movement from traditional ETL (Extract Transform Load) to ELT (Extract Load Transform). The name ELT is self-explanatory as the sequential order of tasks is switched such that loading comes before the transformation, but it takes a little more investigation to understand why the movement has taken place and how it is even possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immediate Reflections on the AWS Solutions Architect Associate Exam (February 2019)</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/aws-solutions-architect-associate-exam-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 15:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/aws-solutions-architect-associate-exam-reflections/</guid>
      <description>I passed the AWS Solutions Architect Associate Certification Exam today and I wanted to write up a few immediate thoughts because I still feel as though the process is somewhat opaque for most people. Part of this may be because of the NDA that you are required to agree to prior to taking the exam. To be clear, everything mentioned in this post will be from a broad perspective and will not include any questions, materials, or test-specific information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Shouldn&#39;t Use ^Parameters with CloudFormation Templates</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/why-you-shouldnt-use-parameters-with-cloudformation-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 15:17:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/why-you-shouldnt-use-parameters-with-cloudformation-templates/</guid>
      <description>^Run-Time (I admit that the title is intended to be clickbait)
CloudFormation has become a popular Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool for organizations that use AWS exclusively as their cloud provider (whether it should be or not is another whole discussion). The tool features the ability to add parameters to your configuration scripts (written in either YAML or JSON). However, I will argue in this post that you should not use parameters in your (top-level) scripts by enumerating Adam Jacob&amp;rsquo;s (creator of Chef) 10 principles of IaC as detailed in his chapter in Web Operations and illustrating how the use of parameters either violates or does not add any further value for each of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dockerfile for Building Ionic Apps</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/dockerfile-for-building-ionic-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 22:33:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/dockerfile-for-building-ionic-apps/</guid>
      <description>Building apps using Ionic is useful for the ability to build for both IOS and Android from the same codebase. However, mostly because Ionic is build on top of the Apache Cordova framework, it can be difficult to make sure your environment is configured with the required version of each build component.
This is where Docker can be helpful. You can create a container that has a consistent environment and run it locally to build your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Linux Command Line Using Docker</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/simple-linux-command-line-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 13:21:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/simple-linux-command-line-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker containers are widely used for developing and running anything from web applications to redis caches. However, they can also be useful for running what can effectively be a light VM (a container operates very differently from a VM, but we are just talking about the use case). I like to use a container for accessing the the Linux command line. However, many users do not know how to run a container in the background and access the shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Kong API Gateway for Go Web Server</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/local-kong-go-web-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 15:52:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/local-kong-go-web-server/</guid>
      <description>This guide will teach you how to run the Kong API gateway locally as a proxy server for a Golang API using Docker.
The Go API Link to heading The Golang standard library has a very simple http library that makes it very easy to spin up a web server. For now, we will build the simplest implementation of a web server. Start by creating a new directory in your go/src/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I am Starting a Blog</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/why-i-am-starting-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 20:18:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/why-i-am-starting-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>I have always been envious of developers who share valuable information on their blog. I have thought for a long time that I wanted to be one of those developers that became famous in programming circles for the insight they shared. However, this also led me to be intimidated by the idea of writing my own posts. How could I ever measure up to these developers?
That mindset changed when I realized how much I had benefitted in work, school, and on personal projects from the blog posts of developers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
