<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RISC-V Bytes on Daniel Mangum</title>
    <link>https://danielmangum.com/categories/risc-v-bytes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RISC-V Bytes on Daniel Mangum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:41:34 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://danielmangum.com/categories/risc-v-bytes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Passing on the Stack</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-passing-on-the-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-passing-on-the-stack/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series on the blog where we explore RISC-V by breaking down real programs and explaining how they work. You can view all posts in this series on the RISC-V Bytes page.
 I once took a class on compilers where my professor told us that a CPU is like a human brain: it can store important data and access it quickly, but there is a limit to the amount of data that can be stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Caller and Callee Saved Registers</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-caller-callee-registers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-caller-callee-registers/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a new series I am starting on the blog where we’ll explore RISC-V by breaking down real programs and explaining how they work. You can view all posts in this series on the RISC-V Bytes page.
 When looking at the generated assembly for a function, you may have noticed that the first few instructions involve moving values from registers to the stack, then loading those values back into the same registers before returning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RISC-V Bytes: Cross-Platform Debugging with QEMU and GDB</title>
      <link>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-qemu-gdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 01:41:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmangum.com/posts/risc-v-bytes-qemu-gdb/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a new series I am starting on the blog where we&amp;rsquo;ll explore RISC-V by breaking down real programs and explaining how they work. You can view all posts in this series on the RISC-V Bytes page.
 To start of the series, we are just going to get setup to do some exploration. I am going to assume you will not primarily be using a RISC-V machine1, so we need to configure our local development environment for cross-platform compiling, emulation, and debugging.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>